<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<sst xmlns="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/spreadsheetml/2006/main" count="433" uniqueCount="357"><si><t>Poverty Responsiveness</t></si><si><t>Power-Balanced Partnership</t></si><si><t>Shared Incentives</t></si><si><t>Sound Financial Mechanisms</t></si><si><t>Proactive Risk Management</t></si><si><t>Modest Performance</t></si><si><t>Good Performance</t></si><si><t>Accountability</t></si><si><t>Transparency</t></si><si><t>Customer Focus</t></si><si><t>Level</t></si><si><t>Question</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The organisational structure of service provision makes no distinction between different roles such as strategic level (board), execution (management), oversight, arbitration (e.g. for consumer claims) etc. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Different bodies are in place and roles are separated but it is not adequate due to e.g. incompleteness or staffing and/or institutional overlaps, overlapping or missing competencies.) </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The organisational structure and role separation is in place, but the interaction between the bodies/actors is not effective. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">An organisational structure is in place with clear role separation (separation of board and management, oversight, arbitration etc), unambiguous allocation of responsibilities and duties and proper interaction between actors. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">How would you evaluate how the sustainable infrastructue project contributes to a clear organisational setup and structure of the infrastructure services in the municipality? </t></si><si><t>To what extent are the existing rules and regulations relating to sustainable infrastructure adequate? Do they provide for reasonable checks and balances?</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The rules and regulations are non-existent or incomplete and allow for arbitrary interpretation. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The existing rules and regulations change frequently and don’t offer a reliable framework for sustainable activities. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The existing rules and regulations are more or less stable, but limit the development of efficient services, and decision-making processes are time consuming. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The rules and regulations are appropriate, comprehensive and clear, provide for clear decision-making processes and provide adequate scope for efficient services and innovative solutions. </t></si><si><t>To what extent are existing rules and regulations enforced in a fair and impartial manner?</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">There is a very low level of enforcement of existing rules and regulations. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Enforcement is inconsistent and depends on the ministers and politicians in charge. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Enforcement is acceptable in most cases. </t></si><si><t>Rules and regulations are enforced in a reliable manner</t></si><si><t>How has the project organisation ensured that various players in your municipality (politicians, administration, service provider etc.) are aware of their accountability and responsibility for effective oversight?</t></si><si><t>Everybody seems to work independently within their sphere of influence. There is no culture of accountability and oversight.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Everybody knows who they are accountable to, but oversight is only sporadic. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">There is an oversight culture in place, but few consequences are drawn from the oversight findings (i.e. no effective accountability). </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">There is a culture of accountability with institutionalized reporting and accountability- structures along the decision-making and execution continuum, and there are appropriate measures and oversight procedures. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">To what extent are sensitive issues such as the awarding of contracts dealt with in a traceable manner? </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Procedure is not traceable, only the outcome is known. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Procedure is traceable, but little information about the award process is available. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Procedure is traceable and information about the award criteria and process are actively communicated. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">How is access to information for the public organized? </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">There is no clear guidance/regulation that defines which documents (e.g. reports, studies or contracts) are publicly available, whether at local or national level. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Access to information needs substantial effort and persistence. Information is usually provided selectively. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">All relevant documents are available to the public on demand (e.g. written request and/or payment for service). </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">All relevant documents are available. There is a written policy in place and contracts contain defined transparency requirements; financing of those activities is clarified. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">How effective are communication activities? </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Insufficient communication channels and communication language seriously limit transparency. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Communication is comprehensible but channels exclude some stakeholder groups. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Transparency is supported through communication design (language, channels, forms, timeliness etc) that enables all customer groups to grasp information. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Additionally, the public is actively informed about their rights and how to obtain information. </t></si><si><t>What is the level of transparency regarding budget allocation, revenue and expenditure on this infrastructure ?</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Neither budgets nor revenues/expenditures are communicated on a regular basis. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Budget is communicated and revenues/expenditures are not made public. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Budget is communicated and revenues/expenditures are available on request. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Budget and revenues/expenditures are communicated actively and with a reasonable level of detail. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">What is the level of transparency regarding the process of service delivery (infrastructure quality, service quality, contract progress, project progress etc.) of the infrastructure project to citizens? </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Information on the status of service delivery (service quality) and on project progress (extension, new facilities etc) is not communicated. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Information is delivered only partially. </t></si><si><t>Information is delivered but always with delay and is not very precise.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Information on status of service delivery and on project progress is communicated regularly and in a timely manner. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">How is transparency realized in contract preparation / renegotiation? </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Information on the contract awarding process / project preparation is not communicated. </t></si><si><t>Information is delivered on the process as such, additional information is insufficient (e.g. with delay, not very precise regarding targets, verifiable indicators, clear timelines etc) and/or access is only given to final versions of documents (or only to parts of those).</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Information is delivered only on the process as such, without access to relevant documents. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Information on the process and progress is communicated regularly, in a timely manner and comprehensively (with relevant information and access to relevant documents ascertained throughout the process). </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">How are outcomes of consultation processes with stakeholders and / or customers (surveys, dialogues, hearings, stakeholder committee meetings etc) communicated to the general public? </t></si><si><t>No consultations exist.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Information on public consultation processes is not communicated to the general public, or only in cases where the information is in favour of the majority. </t></si><si><t>They are communicated roughly.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Information on stakeholder consultation is communicated to the general public in terms of the process and results. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">How is corruption both in strategic issues (e.g. contract award) and daily service issues (whilst using the infrastructure) being dealt with? </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Corruption is the subject of discussion, but no adequate information is provided and no measures are taken. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Information on bribery and corruption is provided, but measures to combat are announced but not implemented, or only in a few “show cases”. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Information on bribery and corruption is provided, but measures to combat it (e.g. improved transparency in processes like procurement, financial transactions etc) are announced but not implemented or are not yet adequate. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">There is a credible anti-corruption policy in place, corruption is made public and reporting on corruption is encouraged (e.g. training for staff, penalties, public anti-bribery-campaign etc) and legal measures are taken where corruption can be established. </t></si><si><t>To what extent is institutional know-how available to fulfill the relevant tasks effectively?</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The capacity of many people in a position of responsibility is rather weak and often not adequate to the task. </t></si><si><t>Frequent changes of key persons at all levels (management, administration, executive-politicians etc) limit the possibility for continuity and strategic development.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The abilities of key persons are rather uneven but measures are in place to improve the situation. </t></si><si><t>Persons in key positions are adequately qualified to fulfill their tasks and responsibilities.</t></si><si><t>Is action taken on public complaints within the framework of existing laws, bylaws, rules and regulations?</t></si><si><t>Public complaints have practically no effect.</t></si><si><t>Only complaints from influential people are addressed.</t></si><si><t>Complaints are addressed but with unacceptable delay.</t></si><si><t>Any complaints are addressed within a reasonable timeframe.</t></si><si><t>Results Orientation</t></si><si><t>In your opinion: Are charges for services from the sustainable infrastructure  reasonable given the level of service provided?</t></si><si><t>No, there is constantly a significant gap: charges are far from being adequate compared to services delivered.</t></si><si><t>The service is not continuous. The tariff would be reasonable if the service was continuous and good.</t></si><si><t>The service delivered remains behind what is promised, but more or less acceptable.</t></si><si><t>Yes, for what is charged the services are ok or good.</t></si><si><t>Consumer rights exist, but they are not known by the majority of customers.</t></si><si><t>A customer charter exists and is communicated.</t></si><si><t>No special attempts are made to figure out the details of the relation between service provider and customer; service users are not seen as customers. Customer relations is primarily seen as a part of PR activities.</t></si><si><t>To what extent are the roles and responsibilities of the sustainable infrastructure towards the customers as well as the related rights of the consumers publicly known?</t></si><si><t>A customer charter exists and is communicated explicitly; the charter sets out roles and responsibilities of the sustainable infrastructure and also the rights of the customers.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">To what extent do customer-friendly complaint procedures exist and how are they implemented/communicated? </t></si><si><t>No formal complaint procedures exist.</t></si><si><t>Complaint procedures exist but they are not customer friendly (high threshold, e.g. no customer care center, only way to file a complaint is through the court).</t></si><si><t>Complaint procedures exist and they are easily accessible, but nothing happens after filing a complaint.</t></si><si><t>Customer complaint procedures are publicly announced and it is easy to file a complaint for all customer groups (place where customers can file a complaint and the way they have to do it). Complaints are taken seriously and addressed in reasonable timeframes.</t></si><si><t>How comprehensible are tariff systems and the bill presented to customers?</t></si><si><t>The bill with the services charged does not inform about details of the calculation and / or the tariff system is not understandable to ordinary customers.</t></si><si><t>The bill merely presents a summary of charges with no explanations.</t></si><si><t>The tariff system is clear and traceable and the bill also reflects the tariff system in the way it is presented.</t></si><si><t>The tariff system is clear and traceable and the bill also reflects the tariff system in the way it is presented; obtaining additional information is straightforward.</t></si><si><t>In what ways are customers’ views integrated into project development?</t></si><si><t>Project development is seen as a technical question and is the task of engineers only.</t></si><si><t>Public attitudes are taken into account only when customers take the initiative themselves.</t></si><si><t>Customers are interviewed (e.g. public meetings, surveys, stakeholder representatives) about their expectations during project preparation.</t></si><si><t>Customers can comment on various service options before final decisions are taken.</t></si><si><t>How is customer satisfaction with utility performance taken into account?</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Services are provided but no feedback and / or customer input is sought. </t></si><si><t>Customers can give feedback at the customer service desk if they want. Sporadic customer surveys may be carried out for internal purposes (no communication of results).</t></si><si><t>Surveys are carried out (at least once every five years) and measures are presented together with results.</t></si><si><t>In addition to general customer surveys, results are aggregated per area (e.g. per municipality district) and integrated with other data (service monitoring, public health, demography etc).</t></si><si><t>Are there procedures in place to assure continuous improvement of customer service?</t></si><si><t>No special procedures are established. Focus is on keeping the system running.</t></si><si><t>Inputs for improvements are accepted, but there is no influence as to what happens afterwards.</t></si><si><t>The sustainable infrastructure strives for improvements but based on their own perception of what is meant by ‘improved customer service’.</t></si><si><t>Yes, a close / institutionalized collaboration between the sustainable infrastructure's departments and customer desk ascertain that feedback is systematically incorporated into the service cycle.</t></si><si><t>There are no specific goals for service levels, activities and projects are based on input levels and not on output targets.</t></si><si><t>Goals are set, but their realization is not based on realistic assumptions.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">How are targets for service levels of the sustainable infrastructure defined? </t></si><si><t>Goals are set and performance targets realistically defined (e.g. based on a long or mid term program) and transferred into measures; or only low involvement of customer related indicators (e.g. satisfaction, complaints) in definition and measurement of results.</t></si><si><t>In addition to the realistically defined performance targets, customers are explicitly involved in the results definition process, and goals and result  are reflected in the annual budget of the sustainable infrastructure / local authority and communicated to the customers.</t></si><si><t>What is done to identify the most effective way to achieve the results and targets?</t></si><si><t>Focus is on technical measures and investment.</t></si><si><t>Operational and managerial measures and improvements within the given set-up are considered too.</t></si><si><t>Studies also cover the appropriate corporate organization / institutional set-up.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Options considered also include cooperation with other (neighboring) utilities, role of small scale providers, cooperation with the private sector etc. </t></si><si><t>The focus is on traditional and well known technologies and approaches.</t></si><si><t>Innovative solutions are not actively sought, but are also not excluded per se.</t></si><si><t>Innovative approaches are tested in pilot projects, but have not yet been used in major projects.</t></si><si><t>Without predetermination, innovative solutions (e.g. local solutions, independent small-scale sub-networks, non-conventional billing-systems etc) are considered as feasible strategies and compared to conventional approaches. Where possible, priority is given to innovative approaches.</t></si><si><t>To what extent are regulation mechanisms in place that can effectively monitor compliance with defined targets in operations and construction?</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">No regulation is in place that compares outcome with targets; no service level agreements are available. </t></si><si><t>Active communication of expected benefits puts some pressure on management to achieve the goals; service level agreements are not detailed enough to serve as an effective steering mechanism.</t></si><si><t>Goals and targets are laid down in the contract and/or (subsequent) annual service level agreements (between public and private partner, but also between sustainable infrastructure and administration) but there is no systematic monitoring.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Additionally, an authorized external body (e.g. regulator) with sufficient capacity monitors compliance with goals and targets and compares benchmarks between different sustainable infrastructures. </t></si><si><t>What are the consequences of non-compliance with standards and/or non-achievement of contractually agreed goals?</t></si><si><t>There are no consequences.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Non-compliance is published. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Fines are set and have to be paid in case of non-compliance according to the details of the contract. </t></si><si><t>Additionally, serious infractions can be identified as breach of contract while good performance can lead to a bonus; details are provided in the contract and/or Service Level Agreements (or similar binding documents).</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">To what extent are staff and / or local contractors trained in order to improve their qualifications and contribute to result orientation? </t></si><si><t>There are no resources for training staff members.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Training is provided sporadically. </t></si><si><t>A specialized unit/person is responsible for training; training is provided to utility staff as well as to staff of local entities working as outsourcing partners or as independent local small-scale providers.</t></si><si><t>Regular training is provided to sustainable infrastructure staff.</t></si><si><t>Does the government have a specific framework in place to protect the poor?</t></si><si><t>No special provisions and commitments  in place on national nor local level.</t></si><si><t>Formal commitment / strategy / vision at municipal level established or reaffirmed within the last five years.</t></si><si><t>Formal commitment at national / state level (e.g. poverty reduction strategy papers, right to basic services) is in place.</t></si><si><t>In addition to a formal commitment by the government, responsibility for social and poverty issues in the sector of the sustainable infrastructure has been assigned to specialized staff in the public administration.</t></si><si><t>To which extent are poor customers identified and monitored?</t></si><si><t>Poverty issues are discussed within the administration based on common understanding without detailed analysis.</t></si><si><t>Poverty mapping exercises or similar measures are carried out.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve"> 'Willingness to pay' surveys are carried out before planning projects in squatter areas.</t></si><si><t>Systematic surveys considering economic and social factors of poverty are carried out periodically to adapt planning of services to changing patterns.</t></si><si><t>A simple mechanism (like increasing block tariffs [IBT] or similar approach) is in place reducing the costs of basic consumption without distinguishing between customer groups.</t></si><si><t>A written subsidy policy was established that makes minimal distinction between customer groups and/or also provides for cross-subsidies.</t></si><si><t>A written subsidy policy is in place adapted to the local situation and the policy is reliably implemented.</t></si><si><t>What kind of subsidies, if any, exist for the use of the sustainable infrastructure?</t></si><si><t>No subsidies are paid for connecting to the sustainable infrastructure.</t></si><si><t>Are incentives in place to encourage private sector actors to provide services to the poor?</t></si><si><t>No incentives are in place nor are such incentives needed.</t></si><si><t>Goals to extend coverage are clearly defined with service levels, timelines, priorities and fines for non-compliance.</t></si><si><t>Private actors  are compensated directly for their effective services for the poor (e.g. by OBA-mechanisms or similar systems)</t></si><si><t>General targets to improve coverage for services from sutainable infrastructure in poorer areas are part of the contract with the service provider.</t></si><si><t>To what extent are technical options and service levels adapted to the needs and possibilities of poor customers?</t></si><si><t>The administration decides on the appropriate service level without consulting customers.</t></si><si><t>Customer representatives have a say in the service level, but ultimately there will only be one solution for poor areas.</t></si><si><t>Customer groups have a say in the technical solution and service level they prefer and are informed about the impact on the related tariffs.</t></si><si><t>Local solutions and local actors are encouraged (i.e. small-scale providers, community based distribution, NGO providers etc with a regulatory or contractual framework in place that gives them a recognized position and also sets quality requirements).</t></si><si><t>Are poverty impact assessments of relevant measures (projects, tariffs, subsidies etc) carried out?</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">No systematic assessment is carried out, authorities rely on the perception of administration and politicians. </t></si><si><t>Stakeholder representatives are asked about their perception of poverty impact.</t></si><si><t>Systematic impact assessment is carried out after project completion.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Systematic impact assessment is carried out during the project design phase and after project completion. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">There are no special programs in place or under discussion. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Programs are under discussion, but implementation is not taking place. </t></si><si><t>Programs are in place, but execution is frequently delayed and output behind targets.</t></si><si><t>Are special programs in place to extend coverageof the sustainable infrastructure in as yet unconnected poor areas?</t></si><si><t>Access to services from ustainable infrastructure in slum areas has improved by more than 20% over the last few years and efforts will continue.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Stakeholders only have a say when they have a personal contact / relation in the planning body. </t></si><si><t>The key representatives of the most influential stakeholders are known and contacts with them exist.</t></si><si><t>There is an institutionalized cooperation platform (e.g. round table, stakeholder committee etc) where issues, methods and timing are defined and stakeholder groups are represented.</t></si><si><t>Besides the main actors there are a number of stakeholders concerned by services provided by the sustainable infrastructure. To what extent does the sustainable infrastructure/municipality explicitly interact with them?</t></si><si><t>Sustainable infrastructure services are only discussed within the administration without involving other parties.</t></si><si><t>No support is being provided to any stakeholder group.</t></si><si><t>General public information meetings are held.</t></si><si><t>Most important gaps are being identified. Based on this analysis, issue-specific training is provided for stakeholder representatives.</t></si><si><t>In addition to issue-specific training, stakeholders are given expert support on technical matters helping them to understand topics, reports ,etc, if necessary.</t></si><si><t>Stakeholders often do not have enough background knowledge and know-how of  issues related to the sustainable infrastructureto play an effective role. How does the municipality cope with this situation?</t></si><si><t>There is no regulation body.</t></si><si><t>The regulation body is part of the public administration.</t></si><si><t>There is an independent regulation body, but it is not yet fully established, or it does not operate as independently as it should.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">How well established is the regulator responsible for the sustainable infrastructure sector, including the municipality and the sustainable infrastructure? </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">There is an independent body that regulates the sustainable infrastructure sector effectively; it is respected as such by all actors and the public and it is financially independent (e.g. from tariffs). </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Where services are contracted out, a balance between the contracting parties is necessary. The roles and responsibilities have to be clear and accepted by both parties. To what extent is this the case in your municipality? </t></si><si><t>Contracting parties show big disparities in their level of know-how, skills and resources, and no capacity building is undertaken.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Minimal capacity building measures exist where major gaps are obvious. </t></si><si><t>Capacity building is actively promoted for the weaker party and its staff and external support is provided.</t></si><si><t>Contracting parties are more or less on an equal footing and can obtain support where necessary.</t></si><si><t>Gender is not a special issue.</t></si><si><t>Experts are interviewed on a case by case basis for specific questions.</t></si><si><t>Women are consulted directly on their needs during project preparation and are encouraged to participate.</t></si><si><t>Women are well represented and actively involved throughout the planning and decision making process.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Conflicts among stakeholders (e.g. over priorities), if serious, can block project preparation or decision making processes. How are such conflicts handled? </t></si><si><t>Decisions are prepared and taken by the administration without taking into consideration real or potential conflicts.</t></si><si><t>Where conflicts arise during project preparation, the municipality stops consultation and takes a decision.</t></si><si><t>The municipality is aware of the problem, but only strives to find solutions in some cases.</t></si><si><t>Procedures are in place to mediate in cases of conflict in order to find solutions that are acceptable to all parties while the final decision remains with the public authorities.</t></si><si><t>This is not an issue being discussed</t></si><si><t>Some stakeholders come up with their position / demands to initiate the debate.</t></si><si><t>Stakeholders are invited to declare expectations and desired priorities.</t></si><si><t>Dialogue with stakeholders is actively sought in order to understand the expectations.</t></si><si><t>To what extent are expectations regarding the future development of services of the sustainable infrastructure made explicit?</t></si><si><t>To what extent are (private) relations and connections that may potentially affect the stakeholder interests made transparent?</t></si><si><t>There is no requirement to make them transparent.</t></si><si><t>Relations have to be made transparent on request/suspicion only.</t></si><si><t>Relations have to be made transparent selectively.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">All relevant connections have to be made transparent. Fines are imposed in the event of non-compliance. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">To what extent are incentives and interests of each party (public and private) understood and accepted? </t></si><si><t>Incentives and interests of each party are not discussed at all.</t></si><si><t>Incentives and interests of each party are discussed but not understood and not accepted.</t></si><si><t>Incentives and interests of each party are discussed and understood but only partly accepted.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Incentives and interests of each party are well understood and explicitly accepted. </t></si><si><t>No discussion on that and also no impact on (local) government decision.</t></si><si><t>Only little discussion without consensus.</t></si><si><t>Political discussion led a minimal consensus.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Public consultation and discussion developed a sufficient consensus on the most important goals and priorities. </t></si><si><t>What is done to mitigate possible negative impacts of planned projects/measures on some stakeholder groups?</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Change processes will always see winners and losers, hence no measure is taken. </t></si><si><t>Negative impacts are only an issue when they are raised by possibly affected groups.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Sensitive issues are addressed explicitly and set out in relation to the overall benefits so as to gain support for the project as a whole. </t></si><si><t>Sensitive issues are addressed explicitly and solutions are developed to mitigate negative impacts.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Are incentive mechanisms in place to encourage utilities to operate in a result-oriented manner? </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">There are no incentives in place. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Incentives are used for single issues, but are not linked to result-orientation. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Incentives have some links to the overall results, but they are not a systematic instrument to foster the main goal. </t></si><si><t>Incentive mechanisms are developed and defined and are focused on the main goals.</t></si><si><t>There is no financial autonomy and no separate budget. Scope for managerial autonomy is very limited.</t></si><si><t>There is limited budget autonomy within the structures of the administration (e.g. ring-fenced department).</t></si><si><t>There is wide budget autonomy, but checks and balances are inadequate.</t></si><si><t>Full autonomy is granted together with appropriate entrepreneurial scope; checks and balances are in place and audited regularly.</t></si><si><t>What extent of financial autonomy does the organizational setup grant to the different providers of the sustainable infrastructure?</t></si><si><t>Real cost structure is not known at all since various costs are drawn from other budgets (e.g. fuel for cars, street repair following pipe replacement etc).</t></si><si><t>Operational costs are known, but costs of capital (principal and interests) are not included.</t></si><si><t>Operational costs and costs of capital are known, value of assets / depreciation is not precisely known.</t></si><si><t>The real costs of service provision and value of assets are fully known.</t></si><si><t>To what extent is the real cost structure of the sustainable infrastructure known?</t></si><si><t>How efficient is the overall collection of revenue and service charges?</t></si><si><t>Weak billing ratio (60-80%) and weak collection ratio (50-70%).</t></si><si><t>Acceptable billing ratio (80-95%) and acceptable collection ratio (70-85%).</t></si><si><t>Good billing ratio (over 95%) and good collection ratio (both over 85%).</t></si><si><t>Very low collection efficiency and less than half of sustainable infrastructure customers receive bills (billing ratio below 60%, collection ratio below 50%).</t></si><si><t>Revenues do not cover operational costs and maintenance.</t></si><si><t>Revenues cover operational costs and maintenance.</t></si><si><t>Revenues cover  operational costs, maintenance, interest payments.</t></si><si><t>Revenues cover costs fully, i.e. operations, interest payments and amortization.</t></si><si><t>What is the extent of cost recovery of the sustainable infrastructure?</t></si><si><t>The tariff strategy is not economically viable and not socially acceptable.</t></si><si><t>The tariff strategy is not economically viable, but takes care of poor customers.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The tariff strategy is economically viable (i.e. calculates tariffs on the full cost of operations, maintenance and investment, sets targets for collection efficiency, and provides effective enforcement mechanisms) but does not take care of poor customers (i.e. not linked to an adequate subsidy policy). </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The tariff strategy is economically viable (i.e. calculates tariffs on the full cost of operations, maintenance and investment, sets targets for collection efficiency, and provides effective enforcement mechanisms) and takes care of poor customers (i.e. linked to an adequate subsidy policy). </t></si><si><t>How can the approach to the tariff strategy be characterized?</t></si><si><t>How do existing financial liabilities (outstanding debts) impact on the financial situation of the service provider?</t></si><si><t>Existing liabilities are huge compared to effective revenues and cannot be serviced fairly.</t></si><si><t>Existing liabilities can scantly be serviced.</t></si><si><t>Existing liabilities are in sound relation to assets value and revenues.</t></si><si><t>Existing liabilities for sustainable infrastructure and its ensuing services are not at all known.</t></si><si><t>How are capital investments (e.g. for grid extensions) being financed?</t></si><si><t>There is no access to external capital except grants from donor agencies, if any.</t></si><si><t>Access to capital for investments (e.g. from multilateral financing institutions) requires securities from third parties (e.g. from government).</t></si><si><t>For capital investments the sustainable infrastructrure/municipality has restricted access to the capital market (bonds, loans) due to its limited financial strength.</t></si><si><t>Capital investments are under long term planning and financed through a combination of equity capital and debt capital; the sustainable infrastructure or the municipality has access to banks and the capital market (bonds, loans etc) due to its financial strength and subsequent creditworthiness.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Overall, how can the risk culture be described? </t></si><si><t>Talking about risks is unusual, risk awareness is low or even inexistent.</t></si><si><t>Risks are generally seen as unavoidable incidences that cannot be influenced.</t></si><si><t>There is partial risk awareness, but risk handling is seen as an issue for specialists.</t></si><si><t>A comprehensive risk culture exists that promotes risk awareness and also includes stakeholders in the risk assessment.</t></si><si><t>How comprehensively is the risk landscape investigated (examples of risk dimensions include demand risk, financial risk, operating risk, construction risk, design risk, political, macroeconomic, environmental risks etc)?</t></si><si><t>Practically no endeavors are made to investigate the risk landscape.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Unsystematic risk-identification. </t></si><si><t>Systematic risk-identification and assessment but not covering all risk dimensions.</t></si><si><t>Processes are defined for identifying commercial and non-commercial risks (e.g. analyzing project sensitivity by altering key variables) including procedures on how to assess them (impact/probability).</t></si><si><t>How high is the risk of inaccurate data?</t></si><si><t>High risk due to very low data accuracy.</t></si><si><t>Moderate-high risk, some key data cannot be judged as reliable.</t></si><si><t>Moderate risk, key data are reliable, but some uncertainties remain in non-key areas.</t></si><si><t>Low risk, data are reliable.</t></si><si><t>Are risks continuously monitored?</t></si><si><t>No system of risk monitoring is in place.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Risk monitoring is conducted for certain risks at random points in time. </t></si><si><t>Risks are monitored before major project milestones, renegotiations etc, but there is no continuous monitoring.</t></si><si><t>Systematic and comprehensive risk monitoring is in place including procedures on how to tackle identified risks.</t></si><si><t>Is there a risk management system with an appropriate mitigation and allocation of risks (each risk taker should be in the position to cover its residual risk exposure)?</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">No explicit risk allocation. </t></si><si><t>Some risks are allocated explicitly but not all players have to take risks even if they could influence the risk profile (e.g. due to the institutional setup, if utility is part of the administration).</t></si><si><t>Most risks are allocated but there is no consensus on risk allocation and implementation of mitigation measures is not monitored.</t></si><si><t>Risks are distributed based on a discussion/evaluation of which part is best able to take / mitigate the risk. Actual risk allocation is accepted by all partners and mitigation measures are implemented and reported.</t></si><si><t>Are any provisions made for the emergence of unanticipated risks?</t></si><si><t>No provisions are made.</t></si><si><t>Only provisions for exit-strategies are made.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Provisions for actively handling unanticipated risks in some risk areas are made. </t></si><si><t>Agreements between partners define how to proceed in case of unanticipated risks and include early warning-mechanisms/monitoring-systems.</t></si><si><t>There are (potential) conflicts with other (competing) uses, but there are no rules or discussions, an abstraction license is not needed.</t></si><si><t>Main competing uses are regulated as a matter of habit / customary law.</t></si><si><t>To what extent is interaction of the sustainable infrastructure with other – possibly competing – resource uses  regulated?</t></si><si><t>Resource abstractions for all users are regulated by a license system.</t></si><si><t>The sustainable infrastructure's resource abstraction is regulated/negotiated balanced with competing uses within an integrated resources management plan.</t></si><si><t>Coverage is high and no further extension is needed.</t></si><si><t>Which is the current state of coverage of sustianable infrastructure provided services?</t></si><si><t>Extension of coverage of such services is low (below 30%), but is declared a priority.</t></si><si><t>Extension of coverage of such services is low (below 30% coveraged) with no or low priority.</t></si><si><t>Extension of coverage of such services has increased over the last 5 years by over 10% and efforts will continue (political commitment and funds are allocated).</t></si><si><t>No explicit standards exist.</t></si><si><t>Do standards exist to regulate resource use and management of resource waste?</t></si><si><t>Standards exist for using resources , but not or only on a very rudimentary level for waste of resources.</t></si><si><t>Reasonable standards (no major negative discrepancies with international standards) for resource use and resource waste management are in place.</t></si><si><t>Monitoring is carried out sporadically and is not comprehensive.</t></si><si><t>Monitoring is carried out systematically, but it is unclear what happens with the results (e.g. no institutionalized reporting or no corrective measures [including fines]).</t></si><si><t>Monitoring is carried out systematically and comprehensively; there are institutionalized ways of following up on the results and for taking adequate measures (including fines).</t></si><si><t>How would you assess the quantitative monitoring system of resources used by the sustainable infrastructure? (availability, level of aquifers, abstraction rate, losses etc).</t></si><si><t>No monitoring of quantitative resource issues is established.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">How would you assess the quality monitoring system of resources used and distributed by the sustainable infrastructure? </t></si><si><t>No quality monitoring of resources used and distributed by the sustainabel infrastructure is established.</t></si><si><t>No environmental aspects are considered when planning investments.</t></si><si><t>Environmental aspects are only considered when demanded from outside (e.g. political pressure, civil society groups etc)</t></si><si><t>To what extent are investment priorities influenced by environmental considerations, especially efficient use of resources?</t></si><si><t>Priority is given to efficient use of resources before investing in new sustainable infrastructures only if it is less expensive.</t></si><si><t>Priority is given to efficient use of resources and other measures to improve demand-side and supply-side efficiency before investing in new sustainable infrastructures even when it is more expensive, within acceptable limits.</t></si><si><t>It is only an issue in situations of selective shortage.</t></si><si><t>To what extent is demand-side resources conservation encouraged?</t></si><si><t>There are no explicit endeavors to encourage resources saving.</t></si><si><t>Education programs / awareness raising programs exist to promote resources conservation.</t></si><si><t>Demand side resources conservation is promoted and coupled with (economic) incentives.</t></si><si><t>Environmental aspects are not an explicit issue.</t></si><si><t>Environmental issues are only an issue when external groups (political parties, civil society groups) raise the issue and have power to put in on the agenda.</t></si><si><t>Environmental standards are in place and monitored; environmental impact assessment is carried out during the planning phase of major projects.</t></si><si><t>To what extent are environmental aspects (e.g. use of chemicals, electricity, in case of construction: land use, impact on habitats etc) considered in the processes of the sustainable infrastructure?</t></si><si><t>Environmental relevant aspects of the sustainable infrastructure operations ( e.g. use of chemicals, electricity) are considered and improved continuously.</t></si><si><t>Self</t></si><si><t>Evaluation</t></si><si><t>Self Evaluation</t></si><si><t>Power-Balanced Partnerships</t></si><si><t>Poractive Risk Management</t></si><si><t>Resource Protection</t></si><si><t>Next</t></si><si><t>Home</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve"> * The Sustainable Infrastructure Project Guidelines, Self-Evaluation and Validation Tool  is an adaption done by Daniel Wiener, Chairman Global Energy Basel and CEO ecos, and André Schneider, Deputy Chairman Global Energy Basel of André Schneider Global Advisory, of the "Guidelines and Principles for Public Private Partnerships in Sustainable Water Management", which were designed in an extensive multi stakeholder and expert consultation process by the consultancies ecos of Basel and BHP of Zurich, commissioned by the Swiss State Secretariat of Economic Affairs (SECO) and the Swiss Development Cooperation (SDC) in cooperation with the re-insurer Swiss Re.

</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The Sustainable Infrastructure Project Self-Evaluation and Validation Tool 
of the Global Energy Basel (GEB) Foundation 
</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Self-Assessment for GEB Grade Sustainable Infrastructure
</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Cambria"/></rPr><t>Rationale of the Global Energy Basel - The Sustainable Infrastructure Finance Platform</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Cambria"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">
It is he infrastructure, in conjunction with their mind-set, that allows people to take the right choices for climate change action. How can they possibly save energy, if the insulation of their house is insufficient? Who can blame them to own and use multiple cars per household, if there is no adequate public transportation system? GEB Grade Sustainable Infrastructure addresses these issues at the root, efficiently and cost effectively.* The GEB Summit brings together project owners and investors who want to participate in this green, equitable and profitable development.

</t></r></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">To what extent are innovative approaches/technologies considered for achieving good sustainable infrastructure and related services? </t></si><si><t>Gender aspects play a crucial role in sustainable infrastructure issues. To what extent are gender issues considered?</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">To what extent is a consensus on major strategic decisions related to sustainable infrastructure intended? </t></si><si><t>Only rudimentary standards exist for using resources.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Only a few elements of the procedure are known, but not enough to instil confidence. </t></si></sst>